Aki linuma

2-34-8 Mejiro, Toshima-ku, Tokyo 171-0031 Japan aki.iinuma@gmail.com 090-2619-1203

Objective

Product and project manager with over 10 years experience in mobile app, retail and E-commerce field, seeking for a position which requires skills in delivering values to customers, setting up and managing digital applications/tools, and ability to get things done in cooperation with multiple internal and external partners.

Experience

2018 – present: Technology Development, McDonald's Company (Japan), Ltd. Senior Manager of Technology Development

Product Management

- · Product Management for McDonald's coupon offering mobile app
 - o Product area: Frontend and backend
 - § Improved CVR of mobile order (add to cart → order completion) by 10 points in 2020.
 - o User research, experience design, user story definition, prioritization, etc.
- Lead of product management team
 - Leading and educating members who are responsible for many different product areas such as POS, kiosks, internal training tools, McDelivery, service desk
- Agile coaching for other projects that are newly implementing agile methodology
 - Internal workshops
 - Hands-on training

2016 – 2018: Digital Business Transformation Services, Fastretailing Co., Ltd. Senior Product Manager, Manager of Frontend Product Management Team

Product Management

- Product Management for a new E-commerce platform to be used globally and by multiple brands under Fast Retailing
 - Product area: Frontend (Cart & Checkout, Navigation, Membership) and UI for internal users (CMS, Order Management)
 - § Reduced 30% of initial training time for internal users as a result of UX enhancement
 - o Product-related activities (Product Roadmap, backlog refinement, etc.)

Project Management

- Project management for existing E-Commerce platforms and mobile apps of UNIQLO, GU, Theory, PLST, and Comptoir des Cotonniers
 - Launched some services including Click & Collect, convenience store delivery
 - § Supported definition of store operations for O2O services
 - o Process management and improvement for the enhancement plan

- § Implemented tools to enhance transparency to the business side
- Managed local and offshore development vendors
- Launched CRM for some brands

2013 – 2016: Digital Marketing, Uniqlo Co., Ltd.

Digital Marketer

New Business Development, Product Management, Project Management

- Launched a new app-based service "UTme!" and made the business profitable from the first month
 - Product management for E-Commerce platform, public iOS/Android app, in-store iPad app
 - § Topped the ranking of App Store in Japan
 - o Managed internal team and development vendors
 - § Released on schedule to meet the campaign schedule
 - Set up in-store booths in some stores including overseas and directed offline events
 - o Arranged tie-ups with other companies
 - o Defined business rules and operations
 - Led EC operations (production, inventory control, logistics, warehouse management, customer support)
 - § Achieved 120% increase of sales vs previous year without increasing the number of team members
 - o Planned and ran digital marketing campaigns

Project Management

- Magic for All project (tie-up with Disney)
 - Planned an area called "UT Factory" of the 5th floor of Shanghai Flagship Store
 - § App/system development, contents/app development for digital signage, floor planning, operation planning, store staff education
 - § O2O campaigns on WeChat
 - § Awarded by company as a project member
- Localized "UNIQLO App" for each market and supported some countries' digital marketing strategies
 - o Rolled out to 10 new markets
 - Managed development vendors

Product Management

- · Planned roadmap for UNIQLO App
- · Created mobile app-related digital marketing plan
 - 10million+ membership registration
- Launched and updated mobile apps (UNIQLO App, UNIQLO Recipe, UNIQLO Weather)
 - Award: One Show (UNIQLO Recipe, 2013)

2007 – 2013: Management Navigator, Sony Digital Network Applications, Inc. Management Navigator

Product Management, Digital Marketing

· Organized and directed the team for a smartphone application "million moments"

- o Achieved more than a million downloads in a year
- Topped the ranking of Google Play (category of photography / free) in Japan, India, Singapore
- · Directed social media accounts (Facebook, Twitter) and blog
- · Arranged tie-ups with other companies

Business Planning

- · Created a business plan and product plan
- · Launched security consulting business, smartphone application business

Area of Expertise

Product Areas:

E-Commerce & Omni-Channel Employee-facing tools Digital signage and in-store digital tools Mobile app

Hard Skills:

Product strategy
Feature definition
UI UX, UX research
Digital tools implementation
Workflow/operation definition

Soft Skills:

Problem solving Team management, team building Leadership

Education

Bachelor of Environmental Information Keio University, Tokyo, Japan Graduation: March 2007 Major: Human Engineering

Skills and Languages

Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, XD Certified Scrum Product Owner, Scrum Alliance Native speaker of Japanese English: TOEIC score of 950

German: Zertifikat Deutsch (B1 on the CEFR)

Chinese: 4th grade of HSK